If the storm doesn't get you... they will
Crawl is a horror, thriller film directed by Alexandre Aja.
When a huge hurricane hits her hometown in Florida, Haley
ignores evacuation orders to look for her father.
After finding him badly wounded, both are trapped by the flood.
With virtually no time to escape the storm, they discover that
rising water levels are the least of their problems.
Haley, played by Kaya Scodelario.
Dave, played by Barry Pepper.
Beth, played by Morfydd Clark.
Wayne, played by Ross Anderson.
Pete, played by Jose Palma.
Marv, played by George Somner.
Crawl is a 2019 American natural horror film directed by Alexandre
Aja, who produced with Sam Raimi and Craig Flores.
It stars Kaya Scodelario and Barry Pepper as a daughter and father who, along with their dog, find themselves trapped in
the crawl space of their home and preyed upon by alligators during a Category 5 hurricane in Florida.
Aja rewrote the original spec script from the Rasmussen brothers to
expand the length of the story and its characters.
The film was officially announced in May 2018, and production started in
Serbia in August with cinematographer Maxime Alexandre.
The film was primarily shot within a warehouse facility located in the
Port of Belgrade and wrapped in September after 41 days.
During post-production, Max Aruj and Steffen Thum composed the film's score while Rodeo FX
took three months to complete the visual effects, including the alligators.
Distributed by Paramount Pictures, Crawl opted out of conventional film screenings
for critics before it premiered in the United States on July 12, 2019.
The film was a critical and commercial success.
It received generally positive reviews for its action, direction, pacing, and visual effects, earning a nomination for Best Wide
Release at the 2020 Fangoria Chainsaw Awards, and grossed $91 million on a $13.5–15 million production budget.
In August 2024, Paramount greenlit a sequel.
The film explores themes of florida, hurricane,
animal attack, alligator, creature.
The tone is dark and intense.